Jordan Rhodes

7414 SWOOPE ST TAMPA, FL 33616 **813.701.4126**

email: jsrhodes15@gmail.com personal website: https://jordansrhodes.com

Professional Summary

I am a highly driven software engineer with an insatiable hunger for knowledge, who is able to add value to every project I am part of. I have spent the last few years working in full-stack JavaScript land, focusing on React and Node.js. One of my biggest strengths is the knowledge and acceptance of my weaknesses. I am constantly working on my own projects to increase my knowledge and experience.

Technologies

HTML • CSS • Javascript • Node.js • React.js • Redux • Draft.js • Immutable.js • Ruby on Rails • SQL • MongoDB • DocumentDB • stored procedures • git • Heroku • AWS • Azure • SCSS • Photoshop • SEO

Experience

APRIL 2018 - PRESENT

Exzeo USA, Inc, Tampa - Senior Developer

- Working on full-stack JS insurance SAAS platform.
- Lead developer for team that owns the front end of the platform. Building and maintaining a suite of apps used to acquire and manage customers for various insurance products, as well as an admin application for managing consumers of the platform.
- Focused on dev and build infrastructure, code reuse between applications (front end and back end), vetting 3rd party libraries before use, building and maintaining a core js library of logic and components.
- Developed contribution guidelines for inner-source projects.
- Maintaining a forked version of create-react-app in order to customize our build process for front end apps, while leveraging the community at large to keep build tools up to date.
- Technologies used: Nodejs, React, Docker, Kubernetes, rabbitmq, auth0, aws, Mongodb.

OCTOBER 2016 - APRIL 2018

AgileThought, Tampa - FavaScript Developer

- Made significant contributions on a very large project that was a cloud based, consuming an ASP.net Web API on Azure, using the 'Command Pattern' to fulfill REST requests.
- Started, lead, and proved out a team focusing on reusable components which directly lead to increased velocity across all teams. Improved overall code quality, test coverage, and developer experience..

- Owned several important features with a focus on reusability and 'inner-source' practices.
 These features were very flexible, and one in particular was reused to the point that it serviced over half of the application's functionality.
- Helped establish standards and core libraries to be used project and company wide. The
 main core library was a collection of React components to be consumed by other teams on
 the project with the explicit goal of writing the components in a manner that would not only
 be performant, but would serve as the basis for how to develop components in the project.
- Assisted in developing a forked version of create-react-app to enable teams to spin up new projects with built-in scripts for testing, linting, sym-linking, and dev/prod builds.
- Javascript libraries used: React, Redux, reselect, redux-saga, Lodash, Immutable, Draft, fixed-data-table, Redux-Form, node, express, hapi, joi, commander, and others.
- Technologies used: JavaScript, ASP.net, Azure, DocumentDB, Git,

JUNE 2016 - OCTOBER 2016

Mercury New Media, Tampa - Developer Technician

- Worked on Node.js and React.js full time. Pioneered React at the company by rewriting an internal employee payroll application (originally written in Angular 1.x).
- Quickly became a vital part of small team leading the company into full stack javascript.
- Owner of a Full Stack Javascript/React Native cross-platform eCommerce application.
 Wrote a RESTful Node.js API that was consumed by a React web app and React Native android/iOS applications. Hand-rolled user auth, shopping cart, and admin area.

APRIL 2016 - JUNE 2016

WeVue, Tampa - Intern Ruby on Rails Developer

- Committed code throughout the stack on a ROR application. Helped implement a web api that was consumed by android and iOS apps.
- Coordinated with Owners, Designers, and other Developers on multiple projects
- Performed QA testing developed QA scripts for both manual and automated testing.
- Created transactional email templates, wired up email service using SendGrid's API.
- Coordinated bug track between Rails, iOS, and Android teams.

SEPTEMBER 2011 - JUNE 2013

WebStarts - Technical Support

- Provided technical support to website administrators using the platform.
- Built custom websites using PHP, JavaScript, HTML and CSS for custom features.
- Lead the company in sales virtually every month during employment.

MAY 2006 - JUNE 2016

Hospitality - Server

- Worked at various fine dining restaurants in the Tampa Bay area as a server
- Became a level 1 wine sommelier at Jackson's Bistro

Education

JANUARY 2006 - MAY 2007

Florida Institute of Technology, Melbourne, FL - Undergrad

Studied Engineering for two years while playing division 1AA baseball.

A Few Things I'm Proud Of

WeVue

wevue.com

First project; completely rebuilt notification generator for emails.

Personal Website

jordansrhodes.com

Personal website, mostly HTML and CSS, with some JavaScript modals. Links to professional info.

E-commerce site for an e-liquid manufacturer

coilbutter.com

Built on wordpress, migrated to shopify, freelance project, very successful marketing campaign.